Preliminary Guide to the Jaroslav Hulka Papers, 1922-2003 and undated (bulk 1968-2000)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession 2003-0123
  - Contents of Box 21: (Box 21)
    - Suciu, Nicolae - Romania, 1993 (Box 21)
    - T Correspondence, 1980-1995 (Box 21)
    - Temperature Charts, undated (Box 21)
    - Howard C. Taylor, Academic Society, 1979-1985 (Box 21)
    - Toxic Shock Syndrome, 1980 (Box 21)
    - Travel, See: Guerresi, Prof. [empty folder] (Box 21)
    - Disposable Trocars, 1990 (Box 21)
    - Tubal Surgery Survey Form, NCMH. undated (Box 21)
    - Training Centers, South Africa, Rossouw, 1978 (Box 21)
    - Trocar See: Endotherapeutics [empty folder] (Box 21)
    - Udry, Dr. Richard, 1975-1982 (Box 21)
    - Ultrasound-Abortion, 1989 (Box 21)
    - Gynecologic Ultrasound, 1988-1990 (Box 21)
    - Gynecology Ultrasound Atlas, 1989-1990 (Box 21)
    - Uhlir, Miloslav M.D., 1989 (Box 21)
    - [Loose Records] (Box 21)
    - [Loose Records Re. Abortion] (Box 21)
    - Ulberg, L.C., Dr., 1961-1982 (Box 21)
    - U Correspondence, 1982-1990 (Box 21)
    - U.S.A.I.D. (Ravenholt, Speidel), 1977-1980 (Box 21)
    - Uterine blood flow, undated (Box 21)
    - U.S. Surgical Company, 1991 (Box 21)
    - United Medical Network, 1994 (Box 21)
    - V Correspondence, 1983-1996 (Box 21)
    - Valle, Rafael, 1992-1994 (Box 21)
    - Dr. Thierry G. Vancaille, 1988 (Box 21)
    - Van Lith Forceps, 1980 (Box 21)
    - Vas Clip Proposal, 1986 (Box 21)
    - Vasectomy and Atherosclerosis, 1969-1982, (2 folders) (Box 21)
    - Vessel Injury in Laparoscopy, 1979-1980 (Box 21)
    - Video Equipment, See: Department Business [empty folder] (Box 21)
    - Dr. Ljubomir Vasilev, 1971 (Box 21)
    - George S. Goldstein, Winthrop Labs (Letters re: ), 1979 (Box 21)
    - Visiting Professors, 1968-1992, (9 folders) (Box 21)
  - Contents of Box 22: (Box 22)
    - Women's Health, See: Hill, Susan, 1981-1986 (Box 22)
    - Wood, 1989 (Box 22)
    - World Federation of Voluntary Surgical Contraception, 1988 (Box 22)
    - W Correspondence, 1980-1994 (Box 22)
    - Wagner, Pat (lawyer, NCMH), 1977 (Box 22)
    - Wake County Family Planning Project, 1968-1969 (Box 22)
    - WCPE Radio, 1991-1995 (Box 22)
    - Edward Weck and Co., Inc., See: Laparoscopy [empty folder] (Box 22)
    - Wells, Ellen, See: Dilapan Study [empty folder] (Box 22)
    - Lars Westrom, M.D., 1979-1980 (Box 22)
    - Wetterman, Pete, undated (Box 22)
    - Wolf Company, See: Laparoscopy [empty folder] (Box 22)
    - Mac Wolf, M.D., undated (Box 22)
    - Wolkoff, Stark, M.D., 9th for the defense, 1973-1976 (Box 22)
    - WHO Endoscopy, 1974-1995, (5 folders) (Box 22)
    - XYZ Correspondence, 1980-1994 (Box 22)
    - Figures, undated (Box 22)
  - Contents of Box 23: (Box 23)
    - Loose Pictorial Records, undated, (5 folders) (Box 23)
    - CV [Cirriculum Vitae]- photos of JFH, n.d (Box 23)
    - Hulka - CV, undated (Box 23)
    - [Loose Record - Article on Hulka Clip] (Box 23)
    - Clip Pregnancy - CDC Paper, 1982-1986 (Box 23)
    - Cystic Fibrosis, 1982-1986, (7 folders) (Box 23)
    - NCMH Request for Reversal, 1983-1985 (Box 23)
    - Adnexal Mass Review, 1994 (Box 23)
    - Adolescence, 1977-1989 (Box 23)
  - Contents of Box 24: (Box 24)
    - Breast, 1988 (Box 24)
    - Contraception, 1987-1995 (Box 24)
    - Teenage Pregnancy, 1992-1994 (Box 24)
    - Tubal Anomalies, 1981-1990 (Box 24)
    - Laser Ablation (Lefler), 1989-1996, (4 folders) (Box 24)
    - MTX Study, 1995 (Box 24)
  - Contents of Box 25: (Box 25)
    - Abortion - Departmental Rotation, 1986-1991, (4 folders) (Box 25)
    - Fetal Monitoring, 1975-1995, (15 folders) (Box 25)
    - MSFC [Medical Students for Choice] Mtg., March 30th, 1995-1996 (Box 25)
    - Planned Parenthood Health Care Reform, 1992-1993 (Box 25)
  - Contents of Box 26: (Box 26)
    - [Loose Records] (Box 26)
    - Planned Parenthood Fed Board, 1993-1994 (Box 26)
    - M.D. Murders '94, 1994 (Box 26)
    - NIH June 1, 1967, Grant: Monitor for Fetal Oxgenation, 1962-1965 (Box 26)
    - Monitoring of Fetal Oxygenation During Labor. (New Application submitted 9/30/66). 1966 (Box 26)
    - NIH - Contraceptive Eval. Branch, 1979-1987 (Box 26)
    - NICHD Consult 11/82, 1982-1983 (Box 26)
    - [NIH Application], 1973-1980, (2 folders) (Box 26)
    - NIH Grant, 1961-1984 (Box 26)
    - Brilliant Ideas, 1935-1969 (Box 26)
  - Contents of Box 27: (Box 27)
    - Grant Juggling, 1970-1972 (Box 27)
    - To Do's, 1970-1984 (Box 27)
    - [Loose Records] (Box 27)
    - Menorrhagia and Pain Following Clip - Cautery- Pomeroy- Vasectomy, 1970-1981 (Box 27)
    - Trophoblast sensitization, 1979-1983 (Box 27)
    - Fertility Tests and Treatment, undated (Box 27)
    - Cow Hysteroscopy, 1979-1981 (Box 27)
    - Hysteroscopies, 1984 (Box 27)
    - Hysteroscopy - Fluid Overload, 1958-1994 (Box 27)
    - Flexible Hysteroscopy, 1993 (Box 27)
    - CO2 Embolism, 1983-2001 (Box 27)
    - Hysteroscopic Tubal Cannulation, 1986-1990 (Box 27)
    - Complication AAGL Talk, Hysteroscopy, 1993 (Box 27)
    - Hysteroscopy Endometrial Ablation, 1987-1994 (Box 27)
    - Hysteroscopy, 1981-1993 (Box 27)
    - I Correspondence, 1988-1993 (Box 27)
    - IBM Data Base, 1994 (Box 27)
    - Immunology, 1972-1981 (Box 27)
    - Incontinence: See: Gyn/Incontinence (Richardson) Surgery [empty folder] (Box 27)
    - Infertility See: Male Infertility [empty folder] (Box 27)
    - Infertility: See: Resolve, Inc. [empty folder] (Box 27)
    - Infertility Retrospective Study, 1967-1976 (Box 27)
  - Contents of Box 28: (Box 28)
    - [Loose Records] (Box 28)
    - Lap Book, Sections 1 and 2, Chapters 1-11 (Box 28)
    - Lap Book, Section 3, Chapters 12-21, Sent 10/2/96 (Box 28)
    - Lap Book, Figures, Chapters 1-21, (2 folders) (Box 28)
    - Lap Book, Figures, Chapters 22-44, (2 folders) (Box 28)
    - Lap Book, Sections 6,7,8, Chapters 30-44, (4 folders) (Box 28)
  - Contents of Box 29: (Box 29)
    - Lap Book, Section 5, Chapters 22-28, (2 folders) (Box 29)
    - Jarolslav F. Hulka, M.D. [Slides] (Box 29)
    - Laparoscopy Textbook Illustrations, (3 folders) (Box 29)
    - [Loose Materials] (Box 29)
    - [Binder of figures and pictorial materials.] (Box 29)
  - Contents of Box 30: (Box 30)
    - [Instructional Package on Laparoscopy] (Box 30)
    - Clip Teaching Manual Text 1976 (Box 30)
    - Hulka Picture Layouts, 1st Born, (2 folders) (Box 30)
    - Dr. Hulka - Office Copy, Selected Bibliography Concerning Sterilization Technique (Box 30)
    - [Laparoscopic Sterilization with Spring Clips, manual] (Box 30)
    - [Loose Materials, Laparoscopic Sterilization with Spring Clips] (Box 30)
    - [Loose Materials, Laparoscopic Sterilization with Spring Clips, clipped together] (Box 30)
  - Contents of Box 31: (Box 31)
    - Why Abortion was Legalized: J.F. Hulka, M.D., UNC Med Sch. Chapel Hill NC [Binder], (2 folders) (Box 31)
    - [Loose Materials on Women's and Reproductive Health], (3 folders) (Box 31)
    - Gerry [Adolescent Pregnancy Prevention Coalition], (2 folders) (Box 31)
    - [Draft copy of Textbook of Laparoscopy, Jaroslav F. Hulka, M.D. and Harry Reich, M.D.], (1 book and 1 folder) (Box 31)
    - [Correspondence re. Textbook of Laparoscopy grouped together in binder] (Box 31)
    - [Loose Materials re. Reproductive Health] (Box 31)
  - Contents of Box 32: (Box 32)
    - Dr. Jerry Hulka, Channel 14 Report [VHS videotape] (Box 32)
    - Congressional Hearing on Abortion, 1989 March 16 [VHS videotape] (Box 32)
    - Channel 9 News/Washington D.C./Oct. 26 '89/11 p.m. [Beta videotape] (Box 32)
    - [Society for Gynecologic Investigation, Meeting Programs] (Box 32)
    - [Publications re. Reproductive Health], (4 folders) (Box 32)
    - [Draft Copy of Textbook of Laparoscopy, Jaroslav F. Hulka] (Box 32)
  - Contents of Box 33: (Box 33)
    - Biomedical Committee for AVS [Association for Voluntary Sterilization], 1973-1986, (4 folders) (Box 33)
    - Clip, 1994-1996, (6 folders) (Box 33)
    - [Unlabelled hanging folder re. Clip, 1993], (3 folders) (Box 33)
  - Contents of Box 34: (Box 34)
    - [Unlabelled folder re. Clip, 1980-1993], (4 folders) (Box 34)
    - [Unlabelled floder re. Clip, 1980-1988], (7 folders) (Box 34)
    - Video Editing File, 1991-1993, (2 folders) (Box 34)
    - North Carolina Mem. Endoscopy Suite, 1974-1993, (3 folders) (Box 34)
  - Contents of Box 35: (Box 35)
    - Laser Surgery, 1980-1985, (2 folders) (Box 35)
    - Blueprints, Laparoscope and Optics, (3 folders) (Box 35)
    - Blueprints, (7 folders) (Box 35)
  - Contents of Box 36: (Box 36)
    - Adhesions, 1978-1990 (Box 36)
    - Planned Parenthood Clip Flap. 6/81, 1980-1981 (Box 36)
    - Clip Migration, 1989-1991 (Box 36)
    - [Unlabelled hanging folder re. Clip, 1973-1996], (7 folders) (Box 36)
    - Blueprints, Laparoscope and Optics, (4 folders) (Box 36)
  - Contents of Box 37: (Box 37)
    - TV Cassettes, 1988-1989, (2 folders) (Box 37)
    - Unfiled Photos, (2 folders) (Box 37)
    - Lap - Prints (Box 37)
    - Clip Failures, Slides and Tissue Clocks [Removed] (Box 37)
    - Top Photos, File - Color photos, Book, (3 folders) (Box 37)
    - [Loose Records of pictorial materials], (3 folders) (Box 37)
  - Contents of Box 38: (Box 38)
    - [Loose records of pictorial materials], (4 folders) (Box 38)
    - A Correspondence, 1990-1995 (Box 38)
    - [Loose materials] (Box 38)
    - Student Health (Abortion), 1987-1989 (Box 38)
    - Eliz. Adams, 1988 (Box 38)
    - Adamyan, undated (Box 38)
    - Adhesions, undated (Box 38)
    - AIDS, 1991-1993 (Box 38)
    - American Board of Obstetrics and Gynecology, 1963 (Box 38)
    - Angelone, Al, 1979-1983 (Box 38)
    - B Correspondence, 1990-1996 (Box 38)
    - [Loose materials] (Box 38)
    - Benagiano, 1997 (Box 38)
  - Contents of Box 39: (Box 39)
    - C Correspondence, 1990-1995 (Box 39)
    - Carolina Pop. Center, 1995 (Box 39)
    - Joel M. Childers, M.D., 1992-1994 (Box 39)
    - Hangchow - UNC, 1980-1981 (Box 39)
    - Dr. Zhao-heng Guo, OB. Gyn., Beijing, Peoples Republic of China, 1985 (Box 39)
    - Zhongshan Medical College - Dr. Peng, 1980-1981 (Box 39)
    - Dr. Enmei Yu, 1981 (Box 39)
    - Dr. Wang Jian-yu, 1984 (Box 39)
    - Canton - Dr. Zhao, 1980-1982, (2 folders) (Box 39)
    - China - Peking (Peking Med. College), 1986 (Box 39)
    - China - General, 1986 (Box 39)
    - [Unlabelled folder-Correspondence from China] (Box 39)
    - Office Competer Equipment, 1988-1995 (Box 39)
    - Clemens, George S., See: Clip, 1987 (Box 39)
    - Collins, Stanton L., M.D., 1987 (Box 39)
    - Dr. R.B. Councell, 1994 (Box 39)
    - Dr. Crist, 1970-1995, (2 folders) (Box 39)
    - Czechoslovakia, 1996-1997 (Box 39)
    - D Correspondence, 1987-1993 (Box 39)
    - ND: YAG Laser Permit, 1989-1990 (Box 39)
    - Department Business '87, '88, '89, 1988-1993 (Box 39)
    - MFPP Fee Schedule, 1982-1994 (Box 39)
    - Department Chair, 1996 (Box 39)
    - Hillsborough Clinic, 1983 (Box 39)
    - Dept. Business-86-Request for Fellowship, 1983 (Box 39)
    - OB Business - Stored materials in Henderson St. Wrhouse., 1977 (Box 39)
    - Design for Vision - Microsurgical Glasses, 1981 (Box 39)
    - James Dingfelder, M.D., 1980-1995 (Box 39)
    - Antonin Dockalek, 1989-1993 (Box 39)
  - Contents of Box 40: (Box 40)
    - Droegmueller File, 1990 (Box 40)
    - 1995 Endoscopic Instruments, 1994 (Box 40)
    - Endometrial Ablation Accreditation Program, 1992 (Box 40)
    - Elmed, Inc. (bi-polar), Karl Hausner, M.D., 1985-1994 (Box 40)
    - F Correspondence, 1988-1995 (Box 40)
    - Family Health International (formerly IFRP), 1988-1995 (Box 40)
    - FH-LH (Factrel) Study See: Ayerst [empty folder] (Box 40)
    - Family Planning See: Wake County [empty folder] (Box 40)
    - F.D.A., 1992 (Box 40)
    - Fertility: Dial A Baby, 1980-1983 (Box 40)
    - Fitness See: Center for Health Promotion and Disease Preven. [empty folder] (Box 40)
    - Flora, John - Attorney, 1994 (Box 40)
    - [Loose materials] (Box 40)
    - Reproductive Surgery form, 1985-1988 (Box 40)
    - Collaborative Infertility Study, 1978 (Box 40)
    - Infertility Patient Forms, 1979 (Box 40)
    - Infertility Studies, undated (Box 40)
    - Filshie Clip: See Clip, 1987-1992, (3 folders) (Box 40)
    - 1987 Filshie Clip Flap, 1972-1995, (4 folders) (Box 40)
    - AVSC meeting 10/2/87, 1987 (Box 40)
    - G Correspondence, 1990-1995 (Box 40)
    - Garcia Regimen, 1971-1976 (Box 40)
    - Gittelman, David, 1994 (Box 40)
    - David Grimes, 1982-1996 (Box 40)
    - Guerresi, Prof., 1988 (Box 40)
    - Hummel, William, M.D., 1990 (Box 40)
    - Dr. Harry Hasson [empty folder] (Box 40)
  - Contents of Box 41: (Box 41)
    - H Correspondence, 1989-1995 (Box 41)
    - Dr. Jouko Halme, 1981-1987 (Box 41)
    - HP-DP Committee, 1986-1987 (Box 41)
    - Hevesy Medical Instruments Corp., 1980 (Box 41)
    - Hill, Susan (Women's Health), 1988-1992 (Box 41)
    - Pak, Chung Ho, 1994 (Box 41)
    - Barbara Hulka, 1970-1996 (Box 41)
    - Hubacher, David, 1994-1997 (Box 41)
    - Humor, 1967-1984 (Box 41)
    - George Huggins, M.D., 1994-1995 (Box 41)
    - Hamou Hysteroscope, 1976-1990 (Box 41)
    - Hysteroscopic fluid overload, 1994 (Box 41)
    - [Loose Materials] (Box 41)
    - [Unlabelled folder with Original Atlas and Parker Illustrations.] (Box 41)
    - [Slides and Negatives Found with Original Atlas and Parker Illustrations.] (Box 41)
  - Closed (Box 42)
    CLOSED to Research
  - Original Atlas and Parker Illustrations, 1998 and undated, (1 folder and 33 envelopes) (Box OS 1)
  - [Charts and Graphs regarding Abortion.] (Box OS 2)
  - [Blueprints of Medical Instruments.] (Box OS 2)
  - [Miscellaneous medical instruments and devices.] (Box OS 3)
  - Posters from the History of Contraception Museum (Opaperfolder 1)